[
  {
    "pregunta": "Selecciona la palabra que se corresponde con el fonema semivocálico /j/:",
    "respuesta": "ambas son correctas.",
    "opciones": [ "jail", "ambas son correctas.", "Yale" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Rachel exchanged her old laptop for a ___; it was much easier to carry around.",
    "respuesta": "tablet",
    "opciones": [ "tablet", "fuse", "television" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If Peter ______ more, he would have passed the exam.",
    "respuesta": "had studied",
    "opciones": [ "had studied", "has study", "has studied" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If I_____you, I would go to the party.",
    "respuesta": "were",
    "opciones": [ "had", "were", "was" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "_______you_____ to the park if it doesn’t rain?",
    "respuesta": "Will/go",
    "opciones": [ "Might/went", "Will/go", "Did/go" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Nothing has changed ___ my place of residence.",
    "respuesta": "except",
    "opciones": [ "likewise", "however", "except" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "¿Cuál de las siguientes palabras se pronuncia con el sonido consonántico /k/?",
    "respuesta": "Ambas son correctas.",
    "opciones": [ "Ambas son correctas.", "Cake.", "Quiz." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If we miss the plane, we ______ by bus.",
    "respuesta": "will go",
    "opciones": [ "might be", "had to go", "will go" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "When does schwa sound occurs?",
    "respuesta": "Unstressed syllables in multi-syllable words and reduced vowel sound of function words.",
    "opciones": [
      "Only reduced vowel sound of function words.",
      "Only unstressed syllables in multi-syllable words.",
      "Unstressed syllables in multi-syllable words and reduced vowel sound of function words."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If Anna was taller, she _____ heels so much.",
    "respuesta": "wouldn’t wear",
    "opciones": [ "have to wear", "wouldn’t wear", "must wear" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If I______you, I would talk to her.",
    "respuesta": "were",
    "opciones": [ "were", "was", "has" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Indica cual de las siguientes palabras es homófona de 'hear':",
    "respuesta": "here.",
    "opciones": [ "here.", "this.", "there." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Everybody looked at the ___ as the movie started.",
    "respuesta": "screen.",
    "opciones": [ "database", "mouse", "screen." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Laura works in a shop ___ in a factory.",
    "respuesta": "as well as",
    "opciones": [ "but", "as well as", "in addition" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “Where do you live?”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She asked me where I lived.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She asked me where I lived.",
      "Indirect style: She said me where I lived.",
      "Indirect style: She said me if I lived."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “Be quick!”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She ordered me to be quick.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She said me to be quick.",
      "Indirect style: She ordered me be quick.",
      "Indirect style: She ordered me to be quick."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “She got married last year”",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She told me that she had got married the previous year.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She said she was married the previous year.",
      "Indirect style: She said me that she had got married the previous year.",
      "Indirect style: She told me that she had got married the previous year."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "When you switch your tablet ___, you see a red light.",
    "respuesta": "on",
    "opciones": [ "with", "on", "up" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "It was getting dark, so Ann ___ the light on.",
    "respuesta": "switched.",
    "opciones": [ "switched.", "off", "ninguna es correcta." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "He___in the television and switched it on.",
    "respuesta": "plugged",
    "opciones": [ "ambas son correctas", "switched", "plugged" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “Don’t do it!”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She ordered me not to do it.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She told me to do it.",
      "Indirect style: She told me do it",
      "Indirect style: She ordered me not to do it."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Una de las principales diferencias entre el inglés británico y el inglés americano es:",
    "respuesta": "las diferencias en la pronunciación de las semivocales.",
    "opciones": [
      "no existen diferentes en el aspecto de la pronunciación de las semivocales.",
      "las diferencias en la pronunciación de las semivocales.",
      "las diferencias en la pronunciación del sonido consonántico /v/."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "But ____ the life in Paris is pleasant and relaxed.",
    "respuesta": "apart from that",
    "opciones": [ "apart from that", "likewise", "but" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "The user entered an invalid ___.",
    "respuesta": "password.",
    "opciones": [ "password.", "log on.", "reply." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Check your inbox; I just sent you an important ___.",
    "respuesta": "email.",
    "opciones": [ "password.", "inbox.", "email." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I am writing to complain_____the poor service I have received_____your sales assistant.",
    "respuesta": "about/from",
    "opciones": [ "for/from", "about/from", "to/at" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Choose the correct form:",
    "respuesta": "in summer.",
    "opciones": [ "at summer.", "on summer.", "in summer." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "_______ to the administrator account that you will use to reset the forgotten password.",
    "respuesta": "Log on",
    "opciones": [ "Log on", "Reply", "Password" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I have ___my work to this email.",
    "respuesta": "attached",
    "opciones": [ "inbox", "email", "attached" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "My brother bought a new car last week.",
    "respuesta": "A new car was bought by my brother last week.",
    "opciones": [
      "A new car bought my brother.",
      "A new car buy my brother.",
      "A new car was bought by my brother last week."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Ella está casada con un periodista famoso.",
    "respuesta": "She is married to a famous journalist.",
    "opciones": [
      "She is married at a famous journalist.",
      "She is married to a famous journalist.",
      "She is married with a famous journalist."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I would love ___ for dinner tonight.",
    "respuesta": "to go out",
    "opciones": [ "to go out", "going", "go" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I like ___ my homework on Sunday mornings.",
    "respuesta": "Ambas son correctas.",
    "opciones": [ "Ambas son correctas.", "doing", "to do" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Selecciona el sonido semiconsonántico que se corresponde con la palabra 'you':",
    "respuesta": "/j/",
    "opciones": [ "/j/", "Ninguna es correcta.", "/w/" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I love____clothes on sales.",
    "respuesta": "buying",
    "opciones": [ "to buy", "buing", "buying" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I hate ____ my bedroom.",
    "respuesta": "tidying",
    "opciones": [ "tiding", "tidying", "to tidy" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Selecciona el sonido semiconsonántico que se corresponde con la palabra 'jale':",
    "respuesta": "Ninguna es correcta.",
    "opciones": [ "/w/", "Ninguna es correcta.", "/j/" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "That restaurant ___ be very good. It's always empty.",
    "respuesta": "can't",
    "opciones": [ "can't", "have to", "must" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "He_____ be at the office, he starts at half past nine.",
    "respuesta": "must",
    "opciones": [ "will", "must", "to" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I _____be studying the whole weekend. I’ve got an exam next Monday.",
    "respuesta": "will",
    "opciones": [ "going", "will", "would" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Countries ____United States and Russia have competed in the past.",
    "respuesta": "such as",
    "opciones": [ "such as", "for instance", "for example" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I studied for the exam, ___ I don't think I did well.",
    "respuesta": "but",
    "opciones": [ "likewise", "but", "except" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I am plugging my ___ into an outlet to charge it.",
    "respuesta": "laptop",
    "opciones": [ "fuse", "television", "laptop" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "¿Cuál de las siguientes palabras se pronuncia con el sonido consonántico /h/?",
    "respuesta": "House.",
    "opciones": [ "House.", "Chat.", "Children." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I have made a digital copy of the document using a ___.",
    "respuesta": "scanner",
    "opciones": [ "plug", "hairdryer", "scanner" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If you_____me, I would_____it.",
    "respuesta": "had asked/have done",
    "opciones": [ "ask/had", "asked/has", "had asked/have done" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "An essay is:",
    "respuesta": "a short, formal piece of writing that deals with a single topic.",
    "opciones": [
      "a short, formal piece of writing that deals with a single topic.",
      "to explain, in a detailed way, what people, places or objects are like.",
      "a spoken conversation that includes at least two characters."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If I ______the lottery, I would travel around the world.",
    "respuesta": "won",
    "opciones": [ "win", "would win", "won" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "If he ______better English, he would move to London.",
    "respuesta": "spoke",
    "opciones": [ "spoke", "speak", "speaks" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "¿Cuál de las siguientes palabras se pronuncia con el sonido consonántico /t/?",
    "respuesta": "Tea.",
    "opciones": [ "The.", "Thefts.", "Tea." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I need a ___ to recharge my phone's battery.",
    "respuesta": "plug",
    "opciones": [ "plug", "toaster", "Ninguna es correcta" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "The property has large terraces, ___ to a solarium.",
    "respuesta": "in addition",
    "opciones": [ "also", "in addition", "moreover" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "The dialogue is:",
    "respuesta": "a spoken conversation that includes at least two characters.",
    "opciones": [
      "to explain, in a detailed way, what people, places or objects are like.",
      "a spoken conversation that includes at least two characters.",
      "a short, formal piece of writing that deals with a single topic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "En la lengua inglesa existen palabras homófonas, que son:",
    "respuesta": "palabras que se escriben y tienen significados diferentes, pero suenan igual.",
    "opciones": [
      "palabras que se escriben y tienen significados diferentes, pero suenan igual.",
      "palabras que, teniendo distintos grafemas, sus significantes son iguales, y por supuesto, su significado también.",
      "palabras que, teniendo los mismos grafemas, sus significantes son distintos, pero su significado es el mismo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “I’ll come and help you at twelve”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She told me that she would come and help me at twelve that day.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She told me that she would come and help me at twelve that day.",
      "Indirect style: She said me that she came and help me at twelve that day.",
      "Indirect style: She told me that she came and help me at twelve that day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Indica cual de las siguientes palabras es homófona de 'ate':",
    "respuesta": "eight.",
    "opciones": [ "eat.", "eight.", "eaten." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Indica cual de las siguientes palabras es homófona de 'marry':",
    "respuesta": "merry.",
    "opciones": [ "merry.", "Mary.", "married." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “We went to the cinema and then to a Chinese restaurant”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She said that they had gone to the cinema and then to a Chinese restaurant.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She ordered that they gone to the cinema and then to a Chinese restaurant.",
      "Indirect style: She said that they had gone to the cinema and then to a Chinese restaurant.",
      "Indirect style: She said that they gone to the cinema and then to a Chinese restaurant."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct Style: “Please get me a cup of tea”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She asked me to get her a cup of tea.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect Style: She asked to please get her a cup of tea.",
      "Indirect style: She asked me get her a cup of tea.",
      "Indirect style: She asked me to get her a cup of tea."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "En la lengua inglesa existen palabras homógrafas, que son:",
    "respuesta": "palabras que se escriben del mismo modo pero cuyos significados son distintos.",
    "opciones": [
      "palabras que, teniendo los mismos grafemas, sus significantes son distintos, pero su significado es el mismo.",
      "palabras que se escriben del mismo modo pero cuyos significados son distintos.",
      "palabras que, teniendo distintos grafemas, sus significantes son iguales, y por supuesto, su significado también."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “Could you explain number four, please?”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She asked if I please could explain number four.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She asked if I please could explain number four.",
      "Indirect style: She ordered if I please could explain number four.",
      "Indirect style: She claim me if I please could explain number four."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "What is one official language in India?",
    "respuesta": "English is an official language in India.",
    "opciones": [
      "English is an official language in India.",
      "Both are incorrect.",
      "French is the official language in India."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Sharon está muy contenta con su nuevo móvil.",
    "respuesta": "Sharon is very pleased with her new mobile.",
    "opciones": [
      "Sharon is very pleased for her new mobile.",
      "Sharon is very pleased with her new mobile.",
      "Sharon is very happy to her new mobile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "The passive voice is used to:",
    "respuesta": "give more importance to the object.",
    "opciones": [
      "both are correct.",
      "give more importance to the object.",
      "give more importance to the subject."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "'I am writing____relation____the job vacancy'.",
    "respuesta": "in/to",
    "opciones": [ "in/to", "to/at", "on/with" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "El inglés americano tiende a:",
    "respuesta": "no doblar consonantes en los casos en los que el inglés británico las dobla.",
    "opciones": [
      "no tener diptongos.",
      "no doblar consonantes en los casos en los que el inglés británico las dobla.",
      "no escribir con mayúsculas al inicio de las oraciones."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Estoy harto de mi jefe.",
    "respuesta": "I am fed up with my boss.",
    "opciones": [
      "I am hungry from my boss.",
      "I am fed up with my boss.",
      "I am upset to my boss."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Es una característica del inglés americano:",
    "respuesta": "haber convertido los pasados de los verbos irregulares en regulares.",
    "opciones": [
      "pronunciar el sonido consonántico /f/ de manera diferente.",
      "haber convertido los pasados de los verbos irregulares en regulares.",
      "los verbos irregulares no pueden convertirse en regulares ni si quiera por el uso del habla."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "En cuanto al cambio en la escritura de los finales de palabras, podemos decir que:",
    "respuesta": "palabras que en inglés británico acaban en '-tre' el inglés americano las acaba en '-ter'.",
    "opciones": [
      "En inglés americano no existe el fonema /z/.",
      "en inglés americano no se pronuncian las 'eses' del final de las palabras.",
      "palabras que en inglés británico acaban en '-tre' el inglés americano las acaba en '-ter'."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Estoy muy unida a mi hermana.",
    "respuesta": "I am very close to my sister.",
    "opciones": [
      "I am very near with my sister.",
      "I am very close to my sister.",
      "I am very near to my sister."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Check your ___; I just sent you an important email.",
    "respuesta": "inbox",
    "opciones": [ "username", "password", "inbox" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I _____call my teacher, I have a huge doubt.",
    "respuesta": "have to",
    "opciones": [ "have to", "should to", "has to" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "___ rumors I've heard, he was fired for stealing from the company.",
    "respuesta": "According to",
    "opciones": [ "For instance", "For example", "According to" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Selecciona la palabra que se corresponde con el fonema semivocálico /w/:",
    "respuesta": "ambas son correctas.",
    "opciones": [ "wool.", "ambas son correctas.", "quiet." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "You've been travelling all day. You ___ be very tired.",
    "respuesta": "must",
    "opciones": [ "must", "can't", "couldn't" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Formal letters are used for:",
    "respuesta": "formal communications.",
    "opciones": [
      "formal communications.",
      "Both are correct.",
      "personal communications with friends or relatives."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "You_____study harder if you want to pass the exam.",
    "respuesta": "should",
    "opciones": [ "can't", "would", "should" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "When I was fifteen, I_____run for an hour without stopping.",
    "respuesta": "could",
    "opciones": [ "could", "can", "will" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "You____smoke here. It is forbidden.",
    "respuesta": "can't",
    "opciones": [ "should", "can't", "can" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "I would hate ____the summer in Seville.",
    "respuesta": "to spend",
    "opciones": [ "to spend", "spending", "sppending" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "He answered the ___ when it was ringing.",
    "respuesta": "phone",
    "opciones": [ "scanner", "television", "phone" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "The sound “B” is very similar to:",
    "respuesta": "“P”.",
    "opciones": [ "“P”.", "“F”.", "“V”." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Click on print and your document should come out of the ___.",
    "respuesta": "printer.",
    "opciones": [ "minguna es correcta.", "printer.", "mouse." ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Direct style: “I’m leaving tomorrow”.",
    "respuesta": "Indirect style: She said that she was leaving the following day.",
    "opciones": [
      "Indirect style: She said she was leaving today.",
      "Indirect style: She said that she was leaving the following day.",
      "Indirect style: She said me that she was leaving the following day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "Elsa is not here and, ___, she can say nothing.",
    "respuesta": "consequently",
    "opciones": [ "but", "and", "consequently" ]
  },
  {
    "pregunta": "He likes______early in the morning.",
    "respuesta": "getting up",
    "opciones": [ "geting up", "getting up", "get up" ]
  }
]